buysafe.com 2016-06-14

# buySAFE | Legal Notices

#### Introduction

At buySAFE, Inc., we take our responsibility to protect the privacy and confidentiality of our user's information very seriously. This Privacy & Security Policy describes how buySAFE collects and uses personally identifiable information that we obtain in the course of providing our services, whether you are a Merchant, a shopper at a buySAFE Merchant site, a user of one of buySAFE's shopping products or a visitor to buySAFE's domain websites.

#### For Merchants 

buySAFE collects information from our Merchants at several different points on our web sites, which we then use to provide our services to you and to operate our business in a way that serves our customers efficiently and effectively.

_Registration for buySAFE's Services_

To apply to become a buySAFE Merchant, you must first complete the application form. The application form will ask for contact information (such as name, email address, phone number and mailing address). 

We collect information about you and/or your business in order to qualify the best merchants on the web. We verify your identity and we use the credit and business information we collect to determine whether you qualify as a buySAFE Merchant. Your contact information is used to explain our services, to send invoices, and to resolve problems related to consumer purchases that involve our services.  
We collect information about you and/or your business from the following sources: 

  1. Information we receive from you on our application or other forms;
  2. Information about your performance in your dealings with us, our buyers, our affiliates or others;
  3. Information we receive from a consumer reporting agency, business credit bureaus and other authoritative sources; and
  4. Information from publicly available online sources.

#### For Shoppers Who Buy from buySAFE Merchants

buySAFE collects information from shoppers who visit a buySAFE Merchant's Web site.  buySAFE collects certain non-personally identifying information such as IP addresses, browser types, domain names, time and date stamps, referring URLs, pages viewed, number of clicks, and other usage data. We use this information to analyze trends, to track visitors' movement in the aggregate, and to gather general information about which pages are visited – all to improve buySAFE services. 

buySAFE collects certain personally identifiable information when a transaction occurs so that we can issue you a guarantee for your purchase from a buySAFE Merchant.

If a Buyer needs to check their benefits, make a claim, report a problem or to report a suspected misuse of the buySAFE Seal, then the buyer must register online and complete a Report a Problem Transaction Form. When filing a claim, we require that buyers provide their name, email address, city, state, country, postal code, name of the web site, URL, and a description of the issue they are reporting. We will use that information to investigate and to resolve buyer benefit claims, including contacting both you and the Merchant as necessary.

buySAFE may use the above data in anonymized or aggregate form to provide and improve its services and to develop new services.

**For All buySAFE Users**

_Information Automatically Collected by our Site_  
buySAFE automatically collects certain non-personally-identifying information through the use of log files, which information such as your IP address, browser type, domain name, time and date stamps, referring URL, pages viewed, and number of clicks. We use this information to analyze trends, administer the site, track visitors' movement in the aggregate, and gather general information about which pages are visited. We may also use this information to improve existing services and to develop new services.

_Cookies, Local Shared Objects, and Add-Ons_  
A browser "cookie" is a small file stored on the visitor's computer that holds information about the visitor. We use both session and persistent cookies. The session cookie is deleted once the visitor closes the browser. A persistent cookie is stored on the visitor's computer for an extended period of time. We may also use a Local Shared Object, which is a small file stored as part of the Adobe Flash Player and commonly known as a Flash cookie. Persistent cookies and Local Shared Objects enable us to maintain user preferences, track and tailor our service to the interests of our visitors, and enhance the overall delivery of our services. Cookies can be removed by the visitor by following browser help-file directions. Local Shared Objects may be managed or removed by visiting the [Adobe Flash Player Settings Manager](http://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager07.html). Local Shared Objects are not used in any way to conflict with a user's personal browser settings.

By allowing a cookie to be set, visitors do not need to log in with a password more than once, which saves time.  All browsers allow the visitor the option to reject cookies.  If visitors reject cookies or Local Shared Objects, they may still use our site, although the functionality will be limited in some areas.

buySAFE uses an outsourced analytics program for understanding usage of our Web site. This application sets a cookie from a third-party domain. This third party is not permitted to use these cookies served on our site for any unrelated purposes.

Those shoppers who choose to install buySAFE's browser add-on may be asked for personally identifiable information at the time of the installation.  This information is used to register the user with buySAFE and to communicate with registered users.

The use of cookies by our partners or service providers is not covered by our privacy policy. We do not have access or control over these cookies. Our partners or service providers use session ID and persistent cookies to make it easier for you to navigate our site.

_Data retention_  
We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. If you wish to cancel your account or request that we no longer use your information to provide you services contact us at customersupport@buySAFE.com. We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

_Clear .gifs_  
Our third party web analytics partners employ a software technology called clear gifs (a.k.a. Web Beacons/Web Bugs), that help us better manage content on our site by informing us what content is effective. Clear .gifs are non-displayed graphics that are used for additional statistical analysis. Clear .gifs are present on most of our web pages for this purpose only. We also use clear .gifs in our HTML-based emails to let us know which emails have been opened by recipients. This allows us to gauge the effectiveness of certain communications and marketing campaigns.

_Profile_  
We may store information that we collect through cookies and/or third parties to create a profile of visitors that interact with the buySAFE services.  This profile is used to tailor a user's visit to our Website and to direct pertinent communications to them.  

_Surveys_  
From time-to-time we request that users participate in a survey. Participation in these surveys is completely voluntary. The requested information typically includes contact information and some demographic information (such as zip code). Contact information will be used to notify the winners and award prizes. All personally identifiable information collected is never shared with third parties, unless the visitor has specifically agreed to such sharing.  While we may use a vendor to conduct these surveys or contests, such a vendor may not use the personally identifiable information for any unrelated purposes.

_Transcripts of Live Chat Sessions_  
_If you use our Live Chat function,_ please note that transcripts of all transmissions are automatically retained, and are available to you for a limited time. We will use the transcripts only in the event that is necessary to resolve an issue related to our service. These transcripts are deleted after they are no longer needed.

We do not disclose, sell or rent any personally identifiable information collected through our services whether publicly available elsewhere or not, except as disclosed in this policy or as required by law.

_Financial Institution Partners/Payment Companies/Bonding Partners/ Vendors_  
We share personally identifiable with our bonding and financial institution partners for the sole purpose of completing the merchant application, delivering a bond or guarantee following a purchase and for resolving transactions that result in a benefit claim.

We may share personally identifiable information we collect to third parties to process credit card transactions or to enable other functions of our service, however, we require that such a third party may not use the personally identifiable information for any unrelated purposes

_Other Third Parties_  
buySAFE may disclose usage statistics that do not contain personally identifiable information to third party web analytics companies.

_By Law_  
Though we will at all times act in a way that respects your privacy, we may need to disclose personally identifiable information when required by law where we have a good-faith belief that such action is required by law, or to prevent or detect a fraud, security or technical issue, or to protect against imminent harm to the rights, property or safety of our users, buySAFE, or the public as required or permitted by law.

_Business Transitions_  
In the event buySAFE is party to a business transition, such as a merger, being acquired by another company, or selling a portion of its assets, personally identifiable information will, in most instances, be part of the assets transferred. In that event the new owner of the company and/or its assets chooses to establish a different privacy policy going forward, it will give notice of that change as well as any choices you may have regarding personally identifiable information.

**buySAFE's Communications to Registered Users**  
We send all those who register with buySAFE a welcome email to verify password and username.  Registered Users may also receive information on products, services, special deals and a newsletter. Out of respect for the privacy of our Registered Users, we allow you to choose NOT to receive these types of communications. Please see the Opt-out section. 

**Opt-out**  
Our Merchants and Buyers from our Merchants may choose to 'opt-out' of having their information used for purposes not directly related to our services.

If you no longer wish to receive our newsletter, special offers, and promotional communications, you may opt-out via telephone, or postal mail. You may also opt-out by [changing your email preferences](https://www.buysafe.com/web/general/unsubscribe.aspx).

The sole exception to this Opt-out option is that we are legally required to send notice of delivery of any bond that is issued and so you may not "opt-out" of that email communication following the purchase of a bonded item. 

**No Spam or Spoofing**  
buySAFE does not tolerate spam or spoofing. To report buySAFE-related spam or spoof emails, please forward the email to [customersupport@buySAFE.com](mailto:customersupport@buySAFE.com)

**Security**  
Protecting personally identifiable information is a top priority.  buySAFE restricts access to personally identifiable information about you only to those employees who need to know that information to provide products or services to you.

buySAFE maintains physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards to eliminate and reduce security and piracy vulnerabilities and to guard personally identifiable information. No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure. Therefore, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.

**Changes to Privacy Policy**  
If we amend this policy at any time, we will inform you of the changes as required by law. We will post changes to this Privacy and Security Policy on our Web site, and other places we deem appropriate, so our users are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances we disclose it.  If we make any material changes to this policy we will notify you by email (sent to the e-mail address specified in your account) or by means of a notice on this Site prior to the change becoming effective. ****

**Updating and Changing Personally Identifiable Information**  
buySAFE provides you with access to your personally identifiable information in our database. You may view and in certain cases update your personally identifiable information (such as zip code, phone, email or postal address) by visiting My Account section of the service center on the buySAFE Web site, [www.buySAFE.com](http://www.buysafe.com/). If you believe that any information is incorrect, or would like to delete/deactivate your personally identifiable information, notify us immediately by either completing a "Contact Us" form or sending an email message to [customersupport@buySAFE.com](mailto:customersupport@buySAFE.com), and we will promptly correct erroneous information or discontinue your service.

**Links**  
The buySAFE site contains links to other sites, including many third party sites such as  [www.libertymutual.com](http://www.libertymutual.com/).  Please be aware that we are not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our site to read the privacy policies of other Web sites.  This Privacy and Security Policy applies solely to information collected by buySAFE's Web sites and other business processes that are within our direct control.

**Questions?**  
If users have any questions about privacy issues or the security of our Web site, you can send an email to [customersupport@buySAFE.com](mailto:customersupport@buySAFE.com)   

**Minors**   
buySAFE's websites, products, and services are neither developed for, nor directed at, children (those under 18 years of age). If you believe your child has provided buySAFE with personally identifiable data, or registered at one of buySAFE's websites, and you would like to have the data removed, please contact us.  

**Non-US Residents**  
Residents of the European Union and other non-US residents who visit or use our site or services understand and consent to the processing of personally identifiable information in the United States.  

If you have questions or concerns regarding buySAFE's privacy policy, please first contact Customer Support by phone at 1-888-926-6333, fax at 703-778-4455, email [customersupport@buySAFE.com](mailto:customersupport@buySAFE.com), or by mail at 1611 North Kent Street, Suite 803, Arlington, VA  22209,  Att: Customer Service. 

[ _This Privacy Policy last updated April 10th, 2013_ ]
